I got something that I bet your math
teacher doesn't even know hey guys this
looks like a fun one did you know that
there are two quadratic formulas anytime
you have ax^2 + BX + cal0 there are two
different quadratic formulas to find
what x could equal you might be familiar
with negative B plus orus < TK of b^2 -
4 a c whole thing over 2 a but there's
also 2 C over the quantity b - + < TK of
b s - 4 a c this quadratic formula will
give the exact same answers as this
quadratic formula would you like see an
example let's try out 3x^2 + 7 x + 2 = 0
the ACs are a little tight let's give us
a little more room and let's do this the
leading coefficient is three which means
a is equal to three so this a will
become three this a will become three
and this a will become three the 7x
means that b is equal to 7 so we'll
change this B to 7 this B to 7 this B to
7 and this bet to 7 and last the
constant is equal to two so we can make
this C2 this C2 and this C2 and now
let's simplify these let's bring down
the -7 and we have plus or minus the
square root 7^2 is equal to 49 and then
we're going to subtract 4 * 3 * 2 which
is equal to 24 and on bottom 2 * 3 is
equal to 6 and then over here 2 * 2 is
equal to 4 we could bring down the -7
and we have minus plus the Square t 7 2
is equal to 49 and then we're going to
subtract 4 * 3 * 2 which is equal to 24
and now we can simplify these on bottom
here here we have the six and on top
here we'll have the four on top we can
copy down the -7 plus or minus Square Ro
T and on bottom we can copy down the -7
minus or plus Square t inside of the
square root 49 - 24 is 25 and same thing
49 - 24 is 25 on the left hand side squ
< TK of 25 is 5 and on the right hand
side Square < TK of 25 is 5 and now
let's smush everything together and
we're ready to finish up we have x
equals and the plus or minus right here
means we're going to have two values of
X both values of X will have a -7 over 6
but the first one is going to be a + 5
and the second one's going to be a
minus5 and on the right hand side the
minus plus means there's going to be two
answers the both have a four and a -7
but the first one is going to be ne5 and
the second one will be + 5 so let's
simplify these top two -7 + 5 is equal
to -2 and let's copy over the six and on
the right hand side we have a 4 and -7 -
5 is -12 both both of these can be
simplified and they both simplify to-
1/3 they both gave the exact same answer
let's put a box around it next let's do
the second one -7 - 5 is -2 and that'll
be over 6 and on this side we can bring
over the four and -7 + 5 is -2 both of
these can be simplified and they both
simplify to -2 once again we got the
exact same answer let's put a box around
it so it actually worked out this
quadratic formula gave the same answer
as this quadratic formula one
interesting observation is this was
minus plus while this was plus minus the
minus version of this gave us the same
answer as the plus version of this and
that will always be true here's another
example where there's only one solution
1/3 both equations gave the same thing
and here's an example with irrational
solutions they both gave the same
irrational Solutions and here's another
example with imaginary Solutions how
exciting so I'm thinking there are two
possible follow-up videos the first has
to show an example of why this is useful
and there is a cool example why it's
useful for another follow-up video we
could actually prove that this always
works I showed a couple of examples here
but we can actually prove this if you
guys want to see either one of those
follow-ups let me know in the comments
how exciting